<section id="build" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

 <title>What is a Build</title>
 <para>In a book on Builds, first question we have to give an answer to is what is Build? Let's start
  with a few generic figures and definitions.</para>
 <figure>
  <title>Build Process</title>
  <graphic fileref="images/build-1.png" />
 </figure>

 <variablelist>
  <varlistentry>
   <term>Build Process or Build</term>
   <listitem>
    <para>A process that takes input and produces output accordingly to
     a specific instructions.</para>
   </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
   <term>Build Artifact</term>
   <listitem>
    <para>Build process output item, usually a file.</para>
   </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
 </variablelist>

 <para>Looks more or less straightforward and simple so far, but not too meaningful. Let's take a closer look at how a concrete instance of Build Process may
  look like:</para>
 <figure>
  <title>Build Process Instance</title>
  <graphic fileref="images/build-2.png" />
 </figure>
 <para>
  In the diagram above, blue arrows shows build process input items, and orange arrows connects build artifacts with the producing process. Any
  build
  process could be uniquely identified with a few properties and set of its input elements.</para>

 <itemizedlist>
  <title>Build Process Properties</title>
  <listitem>Time the build was started</listitem>
  <listitem>Given name</listitem>
 </itemizedlist>

 <itemizedlist>
  <title>Build Process Input</title>
  <listitem>Environment in which process is executed</listitem>
  <listitem>Build process instructions</listitem>
  <listitem>Optional source files and binary artifacts</listitem>
 </itemizedlist>

 <para>
  Note, that at this point we make no principal difference between build environment, build instructions and other kinds of build input, but
  rather stress
  the fact that all these elements are parts of the build input set. Each element of that set could be referenced by
  or described with an unique identifier.
 </para>

 <para>Thus, it is possible to identify any Build Process Instance with an unique identifier as well:</para>
 <variablelist>
  <varlistentry>
   <term>
    Build Process ID = Build Process Properties + (Build Input Item
    <subscript>1</subscript>
    ID, ..., Build Input Item
    <subscript>n</subscript>
    ID)
   </term>
  </varlistentry>
 </variablelist>

 <para>In practice, much shorted identifiers might be and are used, or some part of the full identifier might be omitted with
  no side effects. However, one have
  to keep in mind that such shortened identifiers are unique only in certain
  context which is either limited or implicitly includes omitted information.</para>

 <para>Last note in this section is that, for brevity, Build Process Instance and Build terms are considered synonyms in this book.
  </para>
</section>